[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
[Music]
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
thank you for connecting with us
hope you are doing well let's start our
today's session
through this video i will explain the
overview of tosca workspaces and guide
you to create different types of tosca
workspaces to start our hands-on for
test automation
all right
let's starts with the concepts of tosca
workspace
the tosca workspace is nothing but a
repository to store different components
which are required for test automation
to develop maintain or execute the test
cases we need to connect the workspace
first
the tosca workspace stores the
information of important components such
as modules
test cases
data
execution
requirement
etc for test automation
the workspace has to be defined in local
work system
but the data of tosca workspaces can be
synced to different databases such as
sqlite sql server db2 oracle etc which
can be acted as a shared repository
let's discuss on classifications of
tosca workspaces
two types of workspaces are available
single user and multi-user workspace
[Music]
in a single user workspace only one user
is able to connect and work with tosca
so the central repository is not
required here
[Music]
in a multi-user workspace more than one
users are able to access the workspace
so the tosca workspace has to be created
in central repositories
[Music]
tosca allows to create the workspace in
different databases such as oracle
sqlite db2 sql server etc
in the multi-user workspace the data
management is more simple and easier as
the data are stored in shared databases
which are known as common repositories
to perform any transactions such as add
edit delete in a multi-user workspace we
need to lock the corresponding records
first
it will restrict any other users to
manipulate the same records
after completion of the transaction w
need to unlock the records
in tosca locking of data is known as
check out and unlock is known as check
in before starting of workspace creation
we need to understand the different
values of repository type
based on the selection of this field the
single or multi-user workspace will be
created
it has five different values such as
none sqlite oracle ms sql server and db2
[Music]
if we select the value as none
single user workspace will be created
for other values multi-user workspace
will be created and the selected
database will be used as a central
repository
once we select the appropriate
repository name the database related
field will be appeared such as schema
name connection type etc
in this video we will learn how to
create single user workspace and
multi-user workspace with the help of
sqlite database
all right
now we will learn how to create the
single user workspace
first of all we need to open the tosca
commander and click on create new option
to open workspace creation screen
prior to tosca version 14.x
workspace creation new option was
available in project tab
now we need to enter the mandatory
fields in this screen
as we are creating single user workspace
the central repository is not required
so we will select the option none for
the field type of repository
the path for the new workspace can be
provided here
we will keep the default path and
proceed
after that we have to enter the name of
the workspace which we are going to
create
we are using the name as single user
workspace
the use workspace template option allows
us to include additional components such
as default modules reusables report
templates etc which will help for
automation activities
we can include our own components or the
default one
here we will use the default option
which is required for test automation
now we are ready to create the single
user workspace by clicking on ok button
it will take few seconds to configure
and create the single user workspace
after creation of the workspace success
message will be appear and the close
button will be enabled
[Music]
after closing the window tosca loads the
newly created workspace which contains
the different components of tosca
the default view of tosca workspace
contains the sections such as test cases
modules
requirements
test case design
execution
etc
we will discuss on each of the sections
later
now to view the workspace hierarchy we
need to click on project option which is
available in home tab of the tosca
header
that's all about single workspace
creation
now we will learn how to create the
multi-user workspace
[Music]
first of all we need to open the tosca
commander and click on create new option
to open workspace creation screen
as we are creating multi-user workspace
the central repository is required
so we will select the option based on
our database
if select oracle then we need to provide
the additional schema and connection
string
here we will sqlite option and provide
the corresponding repository path
we will keep the default path and
proceed
[Music]
for first time use existing repository
checkbox should be unchecked
after that we have to enter the name of
the workspace which we are going to
create
we are using the name as multi-user
workspace
[Music]
we can include our own components or the
default one
here we will use the default option
which is required for test automation
now we are ready to create the
multi-user workspace by clicking on ok
button
[Music]
it will take few seconds to configure
and create the single user workspace
after creation of the workspace success
message will be appeared and the close
button will be enabled
while creating the multi-user workspace
we need to connect the workspace through
credential
the default user is admin with empty
password
[Music]
here to update any component first we
need to perform the checkout
[Music]
and after completion of update we need
to perform check-in to save the details
in repository
[Music]
we can view the project and reset the
password by right-clicking on hierarchy
[Music]
that's all about creation of multi-user
workspace
[Music]
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca workspace related
topic
we will learn more about tosca test case
automation in next oscar tutorial please
visit our website lambdageeks.com for
more articles on technology engineering
mathematics and various other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query